（ピノクル）全く　バカな
やんちゃをしたものだね。
Well, you sure screwed up pretty bad.
大事な戦いの前に　おもちゃで
遊んで　ケガするなんてさ。
How did your own toy backfire on you before an important battle?
（ダウト）ムダなく　計画を
遂行するための　最良の手だった。
It was the least wasteful way to complete the plan.
If you had defeated and captured him, then it wouldn't have been pointless...
（メランコリィ）あの男を倒して
服従させられたなら→
意味があったかもしれないけど…。
（ミゼルカ）私たちの　なすべきことは
大門カイトたちとのゲーム。
We should only focus on our games with Daimon Kaito.
ガリレオのスカウトなんて
ムダ以外の何物でもないわ。
What's the point of trying to recruit Galileo?
It's all right. There are no changes to the game.
（フリーセル）いいじゃないか。
ゲームに変更はないんだから。
そうだろう？　ホイスト。
（ホイスト）さようにございます。
Right, Whist?
Indeed.
「これから始まるゲーム
楽しみに見せてもらう…」→
"I am looking forward to watching your next game."
と　クロンダイク様は仰せです。
The words of Lord Klondike.
（メランコリィ）まあ　クロンダイク様が？！
（ミゼルカ）私たちのゲームを。
Ah, Lord Klondike?
He'll be watching our game?
（ダウト）
ぶざまな戦いは見せられんな。
We can't show him an unsightly battle.
（フリーセル）それじゃあ　行こうか。
Shall we go then?
Let's play up.
レッツ　プレー　アップ。
（指を鳴らす音）
lost te saguri de sagashiteta
Lost, trying to find it blindly with my hands.
tozasareta mirai no kotae nante doko ni mo nai
But the key to the locked future is nowhere to be found.
hashiru shoudou ima kaidoku funou
Undecipherable urges surging.
found kudaketa hazu no unmei wo
I found the fate I believed broken.
mijukuna yume no naka de kikoetekitan da
I heard it in my immature dream.
saigo made I'll be there for you
I'll be there for you till the very end.
tachitomaranai kono hari dake wa
I can't stop. I hear nothing else.
boku no asu wo kizamu oto tsukisasu
How this needle carves my future.
shinjitsu kara nigetara ima
I'm running away from the truth now.
genjitsu ni mo maketara ima
I'm losing to reality now.
nani ga nokoru no (nokoru no)
What will be left?
kazoekirenai kono kizu dake ga
The countless scars on my body
boku no kinou wo zanzou toshite kataru
are the only thing telling the story of my past.
unmei ga hodokete mo ima
Even if fate falls apart now,
sonzai wo kowashite mo ima
even if existence shatters now,
boku no michi wo yuku yo
I'm walkng down my own path.
It's now or never.
This is what they say: "Live your life today."
There will always be, there will always be a way.
A Duel Is the Trial of a Puzzle
（キュービック）ファイルナンバー２９。
オレペウス・オーダーに関する考察。
File #29: Investigations Regarding the Orpheus Order.
Until now, I have assumed that the subjects always act as a group of five.
これまで対象は　常に５人で
行動する組織だと考えていた。
だが　今回の単独での
ギャモンへの接触を考えると→
However, the recent attempt of a single member to contact Gammon
案外　一枚岩では
ないのかもしれない。
suggests that they may not always act in unison.
I am going to emphasize the collection of individual data
今後は　個々のデータを
蓄積することに重点を置き→
引き続き　情報収集を行う。　以上。
while continuing to gather additional information. Out.
（ノノハ）ねえねえ　アナ
ここ　いいと思わない？
Check this out, Ana!
Doesn't this place look wonderful?
（アナ）ん～。
話題の注目スポット　プラウダーホース！
Everyone's been talking about the Prouder Horse recently.
イギリスからやってきた
巨大ショッピングモールなの。
It's a huge shopping mall built by a British company.
あ～！　イギリスのスイーツ！　紅茶！
ティーセット！　全部　欲しいの！
British sweets! Black tea! Tea sets!
I want it all!
（キュービック）
買ってくれば　よかったじゃない。
イギリスに行ったときに。
Then you should've bought them...
Huh?
...when we were in England.
あの時は　バタバタして
買い物どころじゃなかったもん。
I didn't have time to go shopping back then.
Hey! Let's go together, Ana!
ねぇ　一緒に行こうよ！　アナ。
（アナ）ん～。
Huh? Prouder Horse?
（キュービック）プラウダーホース…。
Just mini-veggie sandwiches?
ミニ野菜サンドだけ？
（カイト）お前
そんなんで　足りんのか？
Is that enough?
問題ないよ。
必要な栄養素は　十分足りてる。
No problem. It gives me the necessary nutrients.
You know, Q-taro, you can't fight on an empty stomach.
（ギャモン）おい　キュー太郎
腹が減っちゃ　戦はできねえぜ。
キュー太郎って…
忙しいんだよ　僕は。
Q-taro? I'm a busy adult, you know!
But I think... if you don't eat enough, you won't grow big, Q-taro!
アナが思うに　いっぱい食べないと
大きくなれないよ　キュー太郎。
はい。
Yeah.
おじさん！
カレーとチャーハンと牛乳　追加で！
Chef, I'll have curry, fried rice, and milk!
おお！
それでこそ　男の子！
Boys will be boys!
あんたも男の子でしょ。
You're a boy too...
はい　は～い！
みんな　お茶持ってきたよ。
Hey guys, we brought tea!
Tea!
（アナ）お茶！
サンキュー。
Thanks.
大丈夫　キューちゃん？　お茶飲めば？
Are you okay, Cubie? Want a cup of tea?
食べすぎた。
もう　水１滴　入らないよ。
I ate too much. Not even a drop of water would fit.
いきなり　頑張りすぎだろう。
You overdid it for the first time.
Nah, if he keeps going at this rate,
いや　その調子でいけば　すぐに
ギャモンを追い越すんじゃねえの？
he'll catch up to you soon.
おっ？　なんだ　このコップ。
パズルか？
Huh? Nice cup here.
Oh, it's a puzzle?
そう。　アナが作ったんだよ。
Yeah, I made it.
はあ！　よくできてるな！
This is great!
苦心の作。
ふ～ん。
It wasn't easy!
で　あっち…　あっ　あつ　熱くて
パズルが解けねぇ。　あっ　あつ！
Ow!
It's so hot I can't solve it! Ow!
先に　お飲み！
（戸の開く音）
Drink it first!
（ノノハ・ギャモン）ん？！
あっち…　あつ　あつ。
あっ。
（フリーセル）見つけた。
Found you.
You guys!
お前ら！
（コップの割れる音）
何のマネだ？！
ケッ。
What are you doing here?
うはっ。
あっ　オルペウス・オーダー！
The Orpheus Order!
カイト…　あの制服って…。
Kaito, that uniform...
Yeah, it's the Crossfield Academy's.
ああ。　クロスフィールド学院のだ。
That's right, Kaito. We've come from the Crossfield Academy.
そうだよ　カイト。　僕たちは
クロスフィールド学院から来たんだ。
君が　かつて過ごした
あの学舎からね。
From the school where you once studied.
どういうことだ…。
ふふふっ…。
What's going on?
（メランコリィ）この姿を見ても
まだ思い出さないなんて→
We dressed up for you, and you still can't remember?
かわいくないこと。
思い出す？！
You're so not cute.
Remember what?
（ソウジ）それで？　クロスフィールド学院の
君たちが　何のご用かな？
So what are you Crossfield students doing here?
交換留学生が来るって話は
聞いてないけど？
I haven't heard of any exchange students arriving.
（ピノクル）下がっていてくれるかな。
Get lost, chump.
We're here for the children of the Phi Brain.
僕たちは　ファイ・ブレインの子供たちに
用があるんだ。
ふっ…。　大門カイト　逆之上ギャモン
キュービック・ガロア　アナ・グラム→
Daimon Kaito, Sakanoue Gammon, Cubic Galois, Ana Gram:
古きファイ・ブレインの子供たちよ。
the olden children of the Phi Brain.
我ら　オルペウス・オーダーは
正式に　貴公らに対し→
We, the Orpheus Order, formally challenge you,
決闘を申し込む。
right here and now!
決闘…。
A challenge?
We dressed up in uniforms so we could formally invite you to our castle.
正式に　僕たちのお城に
ご招待するために→
こうして　正装まで
してきたってわけ。
うふふっ。　そういうこと。
There you have it.
アジトを見つけられて
やけくそになったか？
You got scared because we found your hideout?
（ダウト）我々は　逃げも隠れもしない。
We do not run or hide.
（ミゼルカ）
もちろん　決闘に応じるわよね。
You'll accept our challenge, right?
ふざけんな！　さんざん
好き勝手　やっておいて。
Kiss my ass!
You've already screwed around a lot,
and now you come with these damn formalities?
いまさら　正式も　くそも
あるかよ！
We promise not to get involved with you anymore if you win.
君たちが勝てば　今後　二度と
関わらないことを約束しよう。
However, if we win, all of you will have to join us in fulfilling our plan -
でも　僕たちが勝ったら　君たちは
オルペウス・オーダーの計画に→
その身をささげてもらうよ。
一生ね。
for the rest of your lives.
うっ。
バッカじゃないの。
Are you out of your minds?!
そんな話　全く受けること…。
受けてやるぜ　その決闘！
There's no one stupid enough to-
We accept your challenge!
全員　ぶっ潰してやるよ。
I'll smash you up so bad,
二度と　ふざけたマネが
できねえようにな。
you won't be able to mess around with anyone anymore.
ちょっと！　ギャモン君…。
そうだね。　そうすれば→
Hey, Gammon, what are-
That's right. You can't get involved with Kaito anymore.
これ以上　カイトに関わることも
ないだろうし。
はぁ？！
アナもやる…　コップの敵！
Me too! I'll avenge the cup!
お前ら　何　勝手に決めてんだ。
Why are you guys accepting so willingly?
断る理由　あるの？
ねえな。
Is there any reason to refuse?
Guess not.
よし　じゃあ　私も行く！
はぁ？
Okay. Then I'm going too!
君のことは　呼んでないんだけど。
No one called you though.
だって　５対４じゃない！
ひきょうよ！
But then it'd be 5v4! You cowards!
うっ。
文句は言わせないわ。
I won't take "no" for an answer.
しかたないな。
おい　待てよ。
Have it your way then.
Hey, wait! Shouldn't Jikugawa be the fifth instead?
あと１人ってんなら　軸川先輩だろ。
うっ。
いや　先輩には
留守番を頼みたいんだ。
えっ？！
No, he should stay and guard home base.
Cubic, are you serious?
キュービック　お前　本気か？
軸川先輩　お願いできますよね。
Jikugawa, we can count on you, right?
分かった。
研究室で帰りを待ってるよ。
Of course. I'll wait for you in your lab.
えっ？！　先輩　来ねえのかよ。
うん。　ご指名も受けてないしね。
Aren't you gonna come?
I wasn't invited anyway.
ノノハ君　みんなのこと頼んだよ。
Nonoha, take care of them.
えっ？！　お　おっす！
Y-Yes, sir!
わ～！　何　これ？
超セレブじゃん。　夢みたい。
Oh my god, look how luxurious this is! It's like I'm dreaming!
ねえ　アナ　見て見て！
あ～！
あぁ！
Hey, Ana! Look, look!
全く　オルペウス・オーダーのやつら→
Seriously, where do these Orpheus guys think they're taking us?
私たちを　どこへ
連れていこうってのかしら？！
（ホイスト）まもなく到着でございます。
We will be arriving soon.
Where? I can't see...
どれどれ？　ん～　見えないなぁ。
キャー！　見て見て！　プラウダーホースよ！
Ah, look! It's the Prouder Horse!
何？　えっ？！　あそこ行くの？
うそ？！　マジで？！　え～っ？！
Are we really going there?
No way! You're kidding, right? Holy crap!
あっ。　あんな所へ連れていって
何をたくらんでいるのかしらね。
What could they possible be planning by taking us there?
As I thought...
やっぱりね。
簡単なパズルだ。
It's a simple puzzle.
プラウダーホースを並べ替えると…。
If you rearrange the letters in "Prouder Horse"...
お～！
オルペウス・オーダーになった。
It's "Orpheus Order"!
So that's their "castle"?
つまり　あれが　やつらの城…
ってわけか。
キャー　超豪華。　ひぃ～！　広～っ！
This is fabulous!
And it's huge!
うわっ　すて…　かわ…　きれ…。
Lovely...
Cute...
Beautiful...
おいしそう。
Looks tasty...
まさか　こんな形で
来ることになるなんて…。
I wish it wasn't under these circumstances.
自由行動しててもいいぜ。
Just go walk around alone.
そんなこと
できるわけないでしょ！
I can't do that!
（ホイスト）まもなく　パズルフロアに
到着いたします。
We will be arriving at the puzzle floor soon.
（ホイスト）こちらへ。
This way, please.
なっ　なに　これ？
（アナ）スケートリンク？
W-What is this place?
A skate rink?
（ホイスト）こちらが　決闘の舞台となる
対戦型パズル→
This is the stage of the battle.
The duel puzzle, Rink Slider.
リンクスライダーでございます。
リンクスライダー。
Rink Slider, huh?
（ホイスト）
リンクの上に　１２枚のスライダーがあり→
There are twelve sliders in the rink.
プレーヤーには　スライダーに乗り　中央の
ゴールを目指していただきます。
The players must stand on them as they head for the center.
（アナ）あ～っ！
ちょっ…　メチャクチャ　高いんですけど。
It's really high...
（ホイスト）プレーヤーは　縦か横に接する
スライダーに移動することができます。
The players may move onto connecting sliders.
乗ったスライダーは　縦横どちらかに
一直線に進ませることができ→
They can also move a slider they are standing on vertically or horizontally.
壁か　別のスライダーにぶつかるまで
止まりません。
It will not stop unless stopped by a wall or another slider.
両者　これを交互に繰り返し→
The players take turns, and whoever reaches the goal first wins.
先に　中央のゴールに着いた方が
勝者となります。
くれぐれも　外からアドバイスなど
なさらぬように…。
Please make sure not to give advice from the audience.
全５ゲームを行い　先に３勝したチームを
勝者とします。　よろしいですか。
There will be five games in total, and whichever team reaches three victories first wins.
Do you accept these rules?
それでは　対戦カードを
決定させていただきます。
Next, we will decide the pairs.
（ギャモン）待ちな！　その必要はねえ。
俺の相手は　ダウトだ！
Hold it!
There's no need for that. My opponent is Doubt.
That's right. I lost the last time as well.
そうだった。　僕も前回
あいつにやられたんだった。
あら　そうでした？
Oh, you did, didn't you?
Hmm... Did I lose too?
あれ～　アナも負けたっけ？
負けたでしょ。
You did.
Hey, don't just decide this by yourselves.
いやいや　勝手に決められても
困るんだけど。
（フリーセル）いや　いいんじゃないかな。
うっ。
No, it's quite all right.
どうせなら　同じ対戦カードで
再戦ってことで　どう？
Just consider them rematches from earlier.
かまわねえぜ。
ふ～ん　まっ　それでもいいか。
Fine with me!
Well, if you say so...
（ホイスト）かしこまりました。
それでは　対戦順を。
Very well then.
Now for the order of the battles.
ファーストゲーム。
キュービック・ガロア様とメランコリィ様。
First game: Sir Cubic Galois and Lady Melancholy.
セカンドゲーム。　大門カイト様とピノクル様。
Second game: Sir Daimon Kaito and Sir Pinochle.
サードゲーム。　アナ・グラム様とミゼルカ様。
Third game: Sir Ana Gram and Lady Mizerka.
フォースゲーム。　逆之上ギャモン様とダウト様。
Fourth game: Sir Sakanoue Gammon and Sir Doubt.
ラストゲーム。　フリーセル様と…。
Last game: Sir Freecell and...
うわっ？！　私が　大将戦？！
んなわけねえだろ！
W-Wait, I'm the final boss?
Like that would ever happen!
じゃあ　カイトが
もう一度　出ればいいよ。
Then you should fight again, Kaito.
分かった。
うふっ。
Fine.
（ホイスト）それでは　ご準備願います。
Please prepare to start.
キューちゃん　頑張れ！
Do your best, Cubie!
心の声
一度戦った相手でよかった。
おかげで　やりやすくなる。
Luckily, I'm fighting the same opponent again.
It's easier this way.
オルペウス・オーダーについては
分からないことが多すぎるよね。
There are too many things we don't know about the Orpheus Order.
あのリングの出どころについても…。
（キュービック）確かに…。
Not to mention the origin of those rings...
That's true.
とにかく　彼らのデータが
もっと欲しい。
At the least, we need more data on them.
心の声
あいつらのデータをいただいて
パズルでも　きっちり　リベンジする。
I'll collect a nice deal of data and take revenge with the puzzle at the same time!
（キュービック）あっ？！　通信できない…。
Transmission failure?
あぁ？　何だ？
キューちゃんの虫メカ？
Huh?
One of Cubie's bug robots?
Let me make something clear.
（ホイスト）１つ申し上げておきます。
このフロアには　妨害電波発生装置が
設置されております。
This floor has an active radio wave scrambler.
電波を使った諜報行為などは
できません。
No gathering of intelligence using radio waves is possible.
キュービック様が先攻です。　お二人とも
準備はよろしいですか？
Sir Cubic has the first move.
Are you both ready?
Anytime.
いつでも　いいですよ。
結構ですわ。
You can start now.
それでは　ファーストゲーム　プレー。
In that case, first game:
play!
心の声
リンクスライダー。　シンプルだけど
高い戦略性が必要だ…。
Rink Slider... It's simple but you need to plan ahead.
心の声
相手の動きを読み　どう
自分の手に組み込むかが　鍵だね。
The key is predicting your opponent's moves and using them against him.
（鼻歌）
うふふっ。
変わった乗り物に
乗ってらっしゃるのね。
That's some weird vehicle you've got there.
乗り物じゃないよ。　友達だよ。
It's not a vehicle; it's my friend!
超音波コントロールなら…。
心の声
Maybe with ultrasonic waves...
あぁ。
ずいぶんお悩みですのね。
You seem troubled. Do you have an upset stomach?
おなかでも痛いの？
うるさいなあ。
Can it.
まあ　心配してますのよ。
心配されても　うれしくないし。
Hey, I'm just worried about you.
That doesn't make me happy.
ふ～ん　そっちに行きますのね。
では　私も　そちらに。
So you're going that way? I'll tag along then.
さあ　次は　どっちに
いらっしゃるの？
Which way next?
うふふっ。
またお会いしましたわね。
We meet again.
うふふっ。
なんで追いかけてくるんだよ。
Why are you chasing me?
あら　なぜ逃げるのかしら？
Why are you running away?
照れてらっしゃるの？
ふふふっ。　かわいい！
Are you embarrassed?
So cute!
私　あなたのこと
嫌いじゃありませんのよ。
I actually might like you.
だって　分かりますもの。
I can understand you after all.
あなたを負かし　傷つけた私に
復讐したいという…→
How you want to take revenge for losing and getting hurt...
That kind of feeling.
その気持ち。
うふっ。
ん　ふっ。
それは　私と同じですもの。
私が戦うのも　復讐のため！
I'm the same!
I'm fighting for revenge as well!
そう！　大門カイトへの復讐のため！
To take revenge on Daimon Kaito!
何？！　俺に…？
Huh? On me?
私　あの男に　もてあそばれ
裏切られ→
He screwed around with me, betrayed me,
身も心も　ズタズタにされましたの！
and made a mess of my heart and body!
カイト…　マジでか？
知らねえよ！
Kaito... Seriously?
I don't know anything!
When he saw the puzzle I made, he just said,
あの男は　私が作ったパズルに対して
かつて　こう言いましたのよ！
「ああ　普通だなぁ」って！
"Ugh, it's so ordinary."
はぁ？！
蝶よ　花よ　と育てられた
この私に向かって…。
I'm a fine lady who was raised bathing in honey and milk!
しかも　覚えてないなんて
ひどすぎるでしょう！
And he says he can't even remember! Isn't that terrible?
でも　これさえあれば→
But with this, I can defeat him and purge him from the face of Earth!
大門カイトを倒し　地面に
はいつくばらせることができるわ。
ぶざまに。
It'll be an ugly sight.
Her eye!
あの目は！
The Orpheus ring is active.
心の声
オルペウス・リングが発動している。
うっ。　もう追いかけてこないの？
Aren't you going to chase me?
あなたが　大門カイトの
お友達じゃなければ→
If you weren't Daimon Kaito's friend, we may have gotten along.
仲よくなれたかもしれませんのに。
残念ですわ。
What a shame.
お断りだね。
I can live with that.
Yes! Cubie's one step from victory!
やった！　キューちゃん　リーチ！
まずいな。
ああ。
えっ？！
This is bad.
Yeah.
かわいくないこと。
So not cute.
追ってくるかと
心の声
思ったのに…　計算が狂った…。
I thought she'd chase me.
My calculations were off.
Her thinking speed is very high now.
心の声
確かに思考速度が上がっている。
（ミゼルカ）メランコリィ　気をつけて。
彼　何か隠してる！
Melancholy, be careful! He's hiding something!
今　いいところだって
分からないのかしら　お姉様！
Sister, can't you see this is not the time for such comments?
（メランコリィ）私の勝ちは決定的ですわ。
それでも　まだ続けますの？
My victory is inevitable. Do you still wish to continue?
（キュービック）当たり前だろ！
こんなとこで　やめてたまるか！
Of course! I can't stop now!
I still have stuff I can do!
僕には　まだ　できることがある！
無理ですわ。
もう　どうにも　できませんわよ。
It's impossible. There's nothing you can do.
これで　私の勝ちですから。
And with this, I win.
ふっ。　それでは　ごめんあそばせ。
If you'll excuse me then.
うふっ。
（ホイスト）ファーストゲーム。　ウィナー　メランコリィ様。
First game, winner: Lady Melancholy.
やりましたわ！　お姉様！
I did it!
Sister, I won!
私　勝ちました～！
よくやったわ　メランコリィ！　はぁ…。
You did great, Melancholy!
キューちゃん。
Cubie...
負けちゃったよ。
キューちゃん　元気出して。
I lost.
Cubie, don't feel bad!
でも　必要なものは頂いた。
But I got what I needed.
パズルの間に　虫メカで
メランコリィのデータを取らせてもらった。
During the puzzle, I gathered data on Melancholy with my bugs.
I thought you couldn't use those because of the scrambling!
虫メカは　電波妨害で
使えないんじゃなかったのかよ。
（キュービック）こんなこともあろうかと
装備しておいた→
I thought that might happen,
超音波コントロールモードが使えたんだ。
so I installed ultrasonic controls as well.
ただし　手動で　コントロールし続ける
必要があったんで→
But I had to control it manually. It was really hard.
大変だったけどね。
ええ　そうです。　今から送るデータを
そちらで解析してください。
Yes. Please analyze the data I'm sending you now.
Yes.
お願いします　メイズ部長。
Thank you, Chief Maze.
よくやってくれたね　エジソン。
You did well, Edison.
え～っ？！　じゃあ　あっ！　虫メカを
操作しながら　パズル解いてたの。
Eh? So...
You were solving the puzzle while controlling the bug?
ずっと？
うん。　でも　負けは負けだよ。
The whole time?
Yeah. But a loss is a loss.
心配すんなって　キュービック。
Don't worry about it, Cubic.
One loss isn't the end of the world.
１敗ぐらい
すぐに取り返してやっからよ。
Yeah!
みんな…　うん。
Guys...
Thanks.
カイト　果たしてもらうよ。
うっ。
Kaito, I'll make you fulfill your promise.
このペンダントにかけても
僕との約束をね。
Even if I have to use my pendant along the way.
約束？
Promise...?
eiyuu kidori itsu datte shinjita muteki no kankaku
I think I'm a hero and believe that I'm invincible.
tatakatte iru no wa chikyuu no tame nanka janai
I'm not fighting for the world.
motto mai peesu de
It's for a more personal,
sou motto shoujikina negai no tame
a more honest wish.
nando to naku kizutsuite mo
No matter how many times I'm hurt